<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/caramessina/remiXML/master/remiXML.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/caramessina/remiXML/master/visualize_remiXML.xsl"?>
<remiXML>
    <metadata>
        <original-title>The Lottery</original-title>
        <doc-title>The Lottery Remix</doc-title>
        <original-writer ID="SJ1">Shirley Jackson</original-writer>
        <remixer ID="CV1">Camila Verdes</remixer>
    </metadata>
    <original>
        <p>The children assembled first, of course. School was recently over for the summer, and the feeling of liberty sat uneasily on most of them; they tended to gather together quietly for a while before they broke into boisterous play. and their talk was still of the classroom and the teacher, of books and reprimands. <question playID="QU1">Bobby Martin had already stuffed his pockets full of stones</question>, and the other boys soon followed his example, selecting the smoothest and roundest stones; Bobby and Harry Jones and Dickie Delacroix-- the villagers pronounced this name "Dellacroy"--eventually made a great pile of stones in one corner of the square and guarded it against the raids of the other boys. The girls stood aside, talking among themselves, looking over their shoulders at rolled in the dust or clung to the hands of their older brothers or sisters.</p>
        <p> <transform playID="T1"> Soon the men began to gather. surveying their own children, speaking of planting and rain, tractors and taxes.</transform> They stood together, away from the pile of stones in the corner,<analysis playID="ANA1">and their jokes were quiet and they smiled rather than laughed</analysis>. The women, wearing faded house dresses and sweaters, came shortly after their menfolk. They greeted one another and exchanged bits of gossip as they went to join their husbands. Soon the women, standing by their husbands, began to call to their children, and the children came reluctantly, having to be called four or five times. <expand playID="EX1">Bobby Martin ducked under his mother's grasping hand and ran,</expand>laughing, back to the pile of stones. His father spoke up sharply, and Bobby came quickly and took his place between his father and his oldest brother.</p>
        <p>The lottery was conducted--as were the square dances, the teen club, the Halloween program--by Mr. Summers. who had time and energy to devote to civic activities. He was a round-faced, jovial man and he ran the coal business, and people were sorry for him. because he had no children and his wife was a scold. When he arrived in the square, carrying the black wooden box, there was a murmur of conversation among the villagers, and he waved and called. "Little late today, folks." The postmaster, Mr. Graves, followed him, carrying a three- legged stool, and the stool was put in the center of the square and Mr.<question playID="QU2"> Summers set the black box down on it. The villagers kept their distance, leaving a space between themselves and the stool. </question> and when Mr. Summers said, "Some of you fellows want to give me a hand?" there was a hesitation before two men. Mr. Martin and his oldest son, Baxter <analysis playID="ANA2"> came forward to hold the box steady on the stool while Mr. Summers stirred up the papers inside it.</analysis> </p>
    </original>
    <play>
        <analysis playREF="ANA1">In this sentence we can tell that there is a very hostile envionrment even though the people are trying to seem like everything is normal. The reader can tell because the pepole are making jokes and they are socializing except that instead of laughing they are smiling making the reader think is it out of respect. The people seem nervous. </analysis>
        <expand playREF="EX1">Bobby's mom seems like a tender and carying women who does not like to reprimand her child and that is why the father has to get involved when it comes to the behavior of their son.</expand>
        <question playREF="QU1">What do the stones respresent and why are they constantly mentioned throughout the text?</question>
        <transform playREF="Trans1">The people began to gather and as they came closer and closer the air became heavier and heavier making the enviorment even more hostile every step they took. The only conversation they had was the talk of the land and what was needed to raise enough crops for the summer.</transform>
        <question playREF="QU2">Why do the people want to keep their distance from the black box and from the stool? Are they in some way trying to show their respect?</question>
        <analysis playREF="ANA2"> The men that came up to hold the box and the stool could be considered the bravest men in the village as they are the only ones who want to show their faces to all the people eventhough they might be the names picked from the box. We can tell that Mr. Martin and Baxter are humble and selfless people.</analysis>
    </play>
</remiXML>