<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/caramessina/remiXML/master/remiXML.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/caramessina/remiXML/master/visualize_remiXML.xsl"?>
<remiXML>
    <metadata>
        <original-title>The Lottery</original-title>
        <doc-title>The Lottery Remixed</doc-title>
        <original-writer ID="AU1">Shirley Jackson</original-writer>
        <remixer ID="RE1">Erica Chen</remixer>
    </metadata>
    <original>
        <p>The children assembled first, of course. School was recently over for the summer, and the feeling of liberty sat uneasily on most of them; they tended to gather together quietly for a while before they broke into boisterous play. and their talk was still of the classroom and the teacher, of books and reprimands. Bobby Martin had already stuffed his pockets full of stones, and the other boys soon followed his example, selecting the smoothest and roundest stones; Bobby and Harry Jones and Dickie Delacroix-- the villagers pronounced this name "Dellacroy"--eventually made a great pile of stones in one corner of the square and guarded it against the raids of the other boys. The girls stood aside, talking among themselves, looking over their shoulders at rolled in the dust or clung to the hands of their older brothers or sisters.</p>
        <p><analysis playID=ANA1>Soon the men began to gather. surveying their own children, speaking of planting and rain, tractors and taxes. They stood together, away from the pile of stones in the corner, and their jokes were quiet and they smiled rather than laughed.</analysis> The women, wearing faded house dresses and sweaters, came shortly after their menfolk. They greeted one another and exchanged bits of gossip as they went to join their husbands. Soon the women, standing by their husbands, began to call to their children, and the children came reluctantly, having to be called four or five times. <expand playID=EX1>Bobby Martin ducked under his mother's grasping hand and ran, laughing, back to the pile of stones. His father spoke up sharply, and Bobby came quickly and took his place between his father and his oldest brother.</expand></p>
        <p>The lottery was conducted--as were the square dances, the teen club, the Halloween program--by Mr. Summers. who had time and energy to devote to civic activities. <expand playID=EX2><transform playID=TRA1>He was a round-faced, jovial man and he ran the coal business, and people were sorry for him. because he had no children and his wife was a scold.</transform></expand> When he arrived in the square, carrying the black wooden box, there was a murmur of conversation among the villagers, and he waved and called. "Little late today, folks." The postmaster, Mr. Graves, followed him, carrying a three- legged stool, and the stool was put in the center of the square and Mr. Summers set the black box down on it. <question playID=QU1><analysis playID=ANA2>The villagers kept their distance, leaving a space between themselves and the stool. and when Mr. Summers said, "Some of you fellows want to give me a hand?" there was a hesitation</analysis> before two men. Mr. Martin and his oldest son, Baxter. came forward to hold the box steady on the stool while Mr. Summers stirred up the papers inside it.</question></p>
   </original>
    <play>
        <analysis playREF="ANA1">It seems like a normal day but there's a hint of some calming factor that causes the men to not have as much energy. It could be that it's a workday or it's hot and sunny but also there appears to be an upcoming group event that doesn't excite everyone.</analysis>
        <expand playREF="EX1">Seeing that Bobby is quite a mischievous and active kid, I imagine that he's quite popular in his social group and gets scolded by adults often.</expand>
        <question playREF="QU1">Why did people stay far from the black box? What could they be drawing for that makes the atmosphere so ominous?</question>
        <transform playREF="TRA1">He was a short grumpy man, very stern and his body rigid. People were sorry for him because his wife died 5 years ago and his son left from home mysteriously one night. </transform>
        <analysis playREF="ANA2">There is an impression that villagers hope their name as well as their family's does not get drawn. It reminds me heavily of the Hunger Games but it seems like this event isn't as forbidding as being forced to participate in a life-and-death match.</analysis>
        <expand playREF="EX2">Last night while Mr. Summers was writing down the 87 names of the villagers late at night and putting them inside the black box, Mrs. Summers reprimands him, saying, "Why didn't you do this earlier. Our candles are almost all out." Mrs. Summers shakes her head and heads to her room to sleep. </expand>
    </play>
</remiXML>
