<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/caramessina/remiXML/master/remiXML.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/caramessina/remiXML/master/visualize_remiXML.xsl"?>
<remiXML>
    <metadata>
        <original-title>The Lottery</original-title>
        <doc-title>The Lottery Remix HW</doc-title>
        <original-writer ID="SJ">Shirley Jackson</original-writer>
        <remixer ID="ED">Erin Devereux</remixer>
    </metadata>
    <original>
        <p>The children assembled first, of course. 
            School was recently over for the summer, 
            and the feeling of liberty sat uneasily 
            on most of them; they tended to gather together 
            quietly for a while before they broke into boisterous play.
            and their talk was still of the classroom and the teacher, 
            of books and reprimands. <expand playID="E1">Bobby Martin</expand> had already stuffed 
            his pockets full of stones, and the other boys soon 
            followed his example, selecting the smoothest and roundest 
            stones; Bobby and Harry Jones and Dickie Delacroix-- 
            the villagers pronounced this name "Dellacroy"--eventually 
            made a great pile of stones in one corner of the square 
            and guarded it against the raids of the other boys. 
            <question playID="Q1">The girls stood aside</question>, talking among themselves, 
            looking over their shoulders at rolled in the dust or 
            clung to the hands of their older brothers or sisters.</p>p>
        <p>Soon the men began to gather. surveying their own children, 
            speaking of planting and rain, tractors and taxes. They stood 
            together, away from the pile of stones in the corner, and 
            their jokes were quiet and they smiled rather than laughed.
            The women, wearing faded house dresses and sweaters, came 
            shortly after their menfolk. They greeted one another and 
            exchanged bits of gossip as they went to join their husbands. 
            Soon the women, standing by their husbands, began to call to 
            their children, and the children came reluctantly, having to 
            be called four or five times. Bobby Martin ducked under his
            mother's grasping hand and ran, laughing, back to the pile 
            of stones. His father spoke up sharply, and <expand playID="E2">Bobby came quickly
            and took his place between his father and his oldest brother.</expand></p>p>
        <p>The lottery was conducted--as were the square dances, the teen club,
            the Halloween program--by <question playID="Q2"><transform playID="T1">Mr. Summers. who had time and energy to
            devote to civic activities. He was a round-faced, jovial man and he
            ran the coal business, and people were sorry for him. because he 
            had no children and his wife was a scold</transform></question>. When he arrived in the
            square, carrying the black wooden box, there was a murmur of 
            conversation among the villagers, and he waved and called. 
            "Little late today, folks." The postmaster, Mr. Graves, followed 
            him, carrying a three- legged stool, and the stool was put in the 
            center of the square and Mr. Summers set the black box down on it. 
            The villagers kept their distance, leaving a space between themselves
            and the stool. and when Mr. Summers said, "Some of you fellows want 
            to give me a hand?" there was a hesitation before two men. 
            Mr. Martin and his oldest son, Baxter. came forward to hold the box 
            steady on the stool while Mr. Summers stirred up the papers inside it.</p>
    </original>
    <play>
        <analysis playREF=""></analysis>
        <expand playREF="E1">Bobby was always seen as a leader. Maybe it was the strength in which he carried his young body or perhaps it was simple from socail cues he picked up on from his father. But no one ever crossed Bobby, the children simply followed his moves.</expand>
        <expand playREF="#E2">No one ever mentions Bobby's little sister. If one were to try and guess how many siblings are in the family they would say, "why two boys". The family tries their best to raise their sons to be loud, proud, and strong while hiding away their little girl as much as possible.</expand>
        <question playREF="Q1">What part of the culture in this village ephasizes these sterotypes of boys and girls?</question>
        <question playREF="Q2">What if he drew out his own name?</question>
        <transform playREF="T1">When I looked down and saw the black spot on my paper, I didnt know what to do. I was silent for some time, until the woman next to me laid her hand upon my shouldern and I realized she has seen what I had. After a moment of contemplating running away or lying, I thought, "at least I dont have kids who will be left alone. Better me than a single mother or father." </transform>
    </play>
</remiXML>