<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/caramessina/remiXML/master/remiXML.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/caramessina/remiXML/master/visualize_remiXML.xsl"?>
<remiXML>
    <metadata>
        <original-title>The lottery</original-title>
        <doc-title>The lottery remixed</doc-title>
        <original- ID="SJ"/>
        <remixer ID="PD"/>
    </metadata>
    <original>
        <p>The children assembled first, of course. School was recently over for the summer, and the
            feeling of liberty sat uneasily on most of them; they tended to gather together quietly
            for a while before they broke into boisterous play. and their talk was still of the
            classroom and the teacher, of books and reprimands. Bobby Martin had already stuffed his
            pockets full of stones, and the other boys soon followed his example, selecting the
            smoothest and roundest stones; Bobby and Harry Jones and Dickie Delacroix-- the
            villagers pronounced this name "Dellacroy"--eventually made a great pile of stones in
            one corner of the square and guarded it against the raids of the other boys.<analysis remixerID="PD" playID="Ana1"></analysis> The girls
            stood aside, talking among themselves, looking over their shoulders at rolled in the
            dust or clung to the hands of their older brothers or sisters. 
            
            Soon the men began to gather. surveying their own children, speaking of planting and rain, tractors and taxes.
            They stood together, away from the pile of stones in the corner, and their jokes were
            quiet and they smiled rather than laughed.<analysis remixerID="PD" playID="Ana2"></analysis> The women, wearing faded house dresses and
            sweaters, came shortly after their menfolk. They greeted one another and exchanged bits
            of gossip as they went to join their husbands. Soon the women, standing by their
            husbands, began to call to their children, and the children came reluctantly, having to
            be called four or five times. Bobby Martin ducked under his mother's grasping hand and
            ran, laughing, back to the pile of stones. His father spoke up sharply, and Bobby came
            quickly and took his place between his father and his oldest brother<expand remixerID="PD" playID="Exp1"></expand>.
            
            The lottery was conducted--as were the square dances, the teen club, the Halloween program--by Mr.
            Summers. who had time and energy to devote to civic activities. He was a round-faced,
            jovial man and he ran the coal business, and people were sorry for him. because he had
            no children and his wife was a scold. When he arrived in the square, carrying the black
            wooden box, there was a murmur of conversation among the villagers, and he waved and
            called. "Little late today, folks." The postmaster, Mr. Graves, followed him, carrying a
            three- legged stool, and the stool was put in the center of the square and Mr. Summers
            set the black box down on it.<question remixerID="PD" playID="Quest1"></question> The villagers kept their distance, leaving a space between
            themselves and the stool. and when Mr. Summers said, "Some of you fellows want to give
            me a hand?" there was a hesitation before two men. Mr. Martin and his oldest son,
            Baxter. came forward to hold the box steady on the stool while <transform remixerID="PD" playID="Trans1">Mr. Summers stirred up
            the papers inside it.</transform> </p>
    </original>
    <play>
        <analysis playREF="Ana1"> The boys exhibit great excitement over the events about to transpire even guarding their stones hoping to keep them away from the other greedy boys </analysis>
        <analysis playREF="Ana2">Something seems off about the men, they are not acting how they usually would</analysis>
        <expand playREF="Exp1">His father was clearly nervous about something, but Bobby was unsure what it was.</expand>
        <transform playREF="Trans1">The crowd went silent as Mr. Summers shuffled the papers inside the box. Everyone knew waht was going to happen but no one would accept the reality of the situation.</transform>
        <question playREF="Quest1">What is it that this ominous box holds?</question>
    </play>
</remiXML>
